window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Discrete_Mathematics - Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 30 (18 Questions)",
  "duration": 50,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Discrete_Mathematics — Slot 30",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Consider the undirected unweighted graph G. Let a breadth-first traversal of\nG be done starting from a node r . Let d(r,u) and d(r,v) be the lengths of the\nshortest paths form r to u and v respectively in G. If u is visited before v during\nthe breadth-first traversal, which of the following statements is correct ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>d(r,u) \\(\\lt\\) d(r,v)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>d(r,u) \\(\\leq\\) d(r,v)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>d(r,u) \\(\\gt\\)d(r,v)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>d(r,u) \\(\\leq\\) d(r,v)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/732/gate2001-2-14#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Seven (distinct) car accidents occurred in a week. What is the probability that they all occurred on the same day? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{7^{7}}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{7^{6}}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{2^{7}}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{7}{2^{7}}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\frac{1}{7^{6}}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/722/gate2001-2-4#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let \\(f:A\\rightarrow B\\)  be a function, and let E and F be subsets of A. Consider the following statements about images. <br> \\(S1: f (E \\cup F) = f (E) \\cup f (F)\\)\n<br> \\(S2: f (E \\cap F) = f (E) \\cap f (F)\\)\n<br> Which of the following is true about S1 and S2? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only S2 is correct</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both S1 and S2 are correct</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of S1 and S2 is correct</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/721/gate2001-2-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following statements:<pre><code>S1: There exists infinite sets A, B, C such that \n    \\(A\\cap(B\\cup C)\\)  is finite.\nS2: There exists two irrational numbers x and y such\n    that (x+y) is rational. </code></pre>  Which of the following is true about S1 and S2? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only S2 is correct</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both S1 and S2 are correct</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of S1 and S2 is correct</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Both S1 and S2 are correct</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/720/gate2001-2-2#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>How many 4-digit even numbers have all 4 digits distinct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>2240</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2296</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>2620</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>4536</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>2296</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/719/gate2001-2-1#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Consider two well-formed formulas in prepositional logic. <br> \\(F1: \\; P\\Rightarrow \\neg P\\)<br> \\(F2: \\;( P\\Rightarrow \\neg P)\\vee ( \\neg P\\Rightarrow P)\\)\n<br>\nWhich of the following statements is correct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>F1 is satisfiable, F2 is valid</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>F1 unsatisfiable, F2 is satisfiable</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>F1 is unsatisfiable, F2 is valid</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>F1 and F2 are both satisfiable</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>F1 is satisfiable, F2 is valid</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/696/gate2001-1-3#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following relations:<pre><code>  \nR1(a,b) iff (a+b) is even over the set of integers\nR2(a,b) iff (a+b) is odd over the set of integers\nR3(a,b) iff a.b &gt; 0 over the set of non-zero rational numbers\nR4(a,b) iff |a - b| &lt;= 2 over the set of natural numbers\n </code></pre>\nWhich of the following statements is correct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>R1 and R2 are equivalence relations, R3 and R4 are not</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>R1 and R3 are equivalence relations, R2 and R4 are not</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>R1 and R4 are equivalence relations, R2 and R3 are not</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>R1, R2, R3 and R4 are all equivalence relations</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>R1 and R3 are equivalence relations, R2 and R4 are not</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/695/gate2001-1-2#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Consider the set of integers {1,2,3,4,6,8,12,24} together with the two binary operations LCM (lowest common multiple) and GCD (greatest common divisor). Which of the following algebraic structures does this represent? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1992)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>group</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>ring</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>field</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>lattice</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>lattice</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43580/gate1992-14b\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:<br>Which of the following is/are a tautology? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1992)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(a \\vee b \\to b \\wedge c\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(a \\wedge b \\to b \\vee c\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(a \\vee b \\to \\left(b \\to c \\right)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(a \\to b \\to \\left(b \\to c \\right)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(a \\wedge b \\to b \\vee c\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/574/gate1992-02-xvi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives ( more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:<br>A non-planar graph with minimum number of vertices has <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1992)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>9 edges, 6 vertices</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>6 edges, 4 vertices</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>10 edges, 5 vertices</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>9 edges, 5 vertices</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>10 edges, 5 vertices</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/563/gate1992-02-viii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following predicate calculus statements is/are valid? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1992)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((\\forall (x)) P(x) \\vee (\\forall(x))Q(x) \\implies (\\forall (x)) (P(x) \\vee Q(x))\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((\\exists (x)) P(x) \\wedge (\\exists (x))Q(x) \\implies (\\exists (x)) (P(x) \\wedge Q(x))\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((\\forall (x)) (P(x) \\vee Q(x)) \\implies (\\forall (x)) P(x) \\vee (\\forall (x)) Q(x)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\((\\exists (x)) (P(x) \\vee Q(x)) \\implies \\sim (\\forall (x)) P(x) \\vee (\\exists (x)) Q(x)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((\\forall (x)) P(x) \\vee (\\forall(x))Q(x) \\implies (\\forall (x)) (P(x) \\vee Q(x))\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/256/gate1992-92-xv\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:\n<br>\nIf \\(F_1\\), \\(F_2\\) and \\(F_3\\) are propositional formulae such that \\(F_1 \\land F_2 \\rightarrow F_3\\) and \\(F_1 \\land F_2 \\rightarrow \\sim F_3\\) are both tautologies, then which of the following is true: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Both\\(F_1\\) and \\(F_2\\) are tautologies</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The conjunction \\(F_1 \\land F_2\\) is not satisfiable</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Neither is tautologous</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither is satisfiable</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>The conjunction \\(F_1 \\land F_2\\) is not satisfiable</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/526/gate1991-03-xii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (More than one may be correct).<br>\nA graph is planar if and only if, <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1990)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>It does not contain subgraphs homeomorphic to \\(k_{5}\\) and \\(k_{3, 3}\\).</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>It does not contain subgraphs isomorphic to \\(k_{5}\\) or \\(k_{3, 3}\\).</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>It does not contain a subgraph isomorphic to \\(k_{5}\\) or \\(k_{3, 3}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>It does not contain a subgraph homeomorphic to \\(k_{5}\\) or \\(k_{3, 3}\\).</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>It does not contain a subgraph homeomorphic to \\(k_{5}\\) or \\(k_{3, 3}\\).</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/85384/gate1990-3-xi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (More than one may be correct).<br>Indicate which of the following well-formed formulae are valid: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1990)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\left(P\\Rightarrow Q\\right) {\\wedge} \\left(Q \\Rightarrow R\\right) \\Rightarrow \\left(P \\Rightarrow R\\right)\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\left(P\\Rightarrow Q\\right) \\Rightarrow \\left( \\neg P \\Rightarrow \\neg Q\\right)\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\left(P{\\wedge} \\left(\\neg P \\vee \\neg Q\\right)\\right) \\Rightarrow Q\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\left(P \\Rightarrow R\\right) \\vee \\left(Q \\Rightarrow R\\right) \\Rightarrow \\left(\\left(P \\vee Q \\right) \\Rightarrow R\\right)\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\left(P\\Rightarrow Q\\right) {\\wedge} \\left(Q \\Rightarrow R\\right) \\Rightarrow \\left(P \\Rightarrow R\\right)\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/84861/gate1990-3-x\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (More than one may be correct).<br>The number of ways in which 5 A's, 5 B's and 5 C's can be arranged in a row is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1990)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(15!/(5!)^{3}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>15!</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\left(\\frac{15}{5}\\right)\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(15!(5!3!).\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(15!/(5!)^{3}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/84841/gate1990-3-ix\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "<p>Answer the following:<br>Which of the following statements are FALSE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1989)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>For poisson distribution, the mean is twice the variance.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>In queuing theory, if arrivals occur according to poisson distribution, then the inter-arrival time is exponentially distributed.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The distribution of waiting time is independent of the service discipline used in selecting the waiting customers for service.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>If the time between successive arrivals is exponential, then the time between the occurences of every third arrival is also exponential.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>For poisson distribution, the mean is twice the variance.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/87141/gate1989-3-vii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "<p>Answer the following:<br>Which of the following well-formed formulas are equivalent? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1989)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(P \\rightarrow Q\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\neg Q \\rightarrow \\neg P\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\neg P \\vee Q\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\neg Q \\rightarrow P\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(P \\rightarrow Q\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/87126/gate1989-3-v\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "<p>If \\(f(x_{i}).f(x_{i+1}) \\lt 0\\) then <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1987)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>There must be a root of f(x) between \\(x_i\\) and \\(x_{i+1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>There need not be a root of f(x) between \\(x_{i}\\) and \\(x_{i+1}\\).</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>There fourth derivative of f(x) with respect to x vanishes at \\(x_{i}\\).</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The fourth derivative of f(x) with respect to x vanishes at \\(x_{i+1}\\).</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>There must be a root of f(x) between \\(x_i\\) and \\(x_{i+1}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/80571/gate1987-1-xxvi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
